

800 King Edward Ave (5052) Ottawa, ON K1N CANADA □ 613 866 7744 | ■ vncprado@gmail.com | 🎓 vncprado.github.io | 🖸 vncprado | 🛅 pradovinicius

## Summary.

I am a computer scientist finishing my Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering, seeking opportunities in the IT industry with excellent interpersonal skills. I have a strong background in developing prototypes and supporting research teams over the previous four years of teaching and research assistant experience. I also have strong knowledge of machine learning and neural networks and software development, especially in Python and C++, in addition to embedded systems, IoT, ROS and tactile sensors. I expanded this knowledge by teaching, among other topics, digital systems and operating systems during my experience at the University of Ottawa. During recent years I have worked with robotic object recognition and tactile sensing for object pose estimation. I also have around one and a half prior years of experience in software development within research laboratories.

## Work Experience

**University of Ottawa** 

Ottawa, Canada

TEACHING ASSISTANT Sep. 2015 - PRESENT

- Provide insights to students on leading technologies, such as, Python, C++, FPGA, VHDL, Android, Arduino, Linux, among others.
- · Assisted professors in eight different courses with group and one-to-one discussions in lectures, Q&A sessions and hands-on activities.
- A was TA for courses including but not limited to: Computer Architecture, Capstone Project and Operating Systems.

• Follow procedures know and abide by the policies and procedures the institution has in place

**University of Ottawa** 

Ottawa, Canada

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jan. 2015 - PRESENT · Provide operational and administrative support to Research Manager, with several tasks among others, writing technical papers, implement

- testing methods, oversee experiments and produce results. • Develop experiments using cutting edge techno which include but are not limited to: C++, Python, Linux, micro-controllers, SoC, tactile
- sensors, IMU, robotic operating system (ROS). • Follow safety and health procedures in conformation to which the institution has in place.

## **National Laboratory of Scientific Computing**

Petrópolis, Brazil

RESEARCHER

Fev. 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Research on cryptography working with a team of PhD and master students implementing algorithms using C++ and Python.
- Develop experiments using Massively Parallel Processors (MPI)

#### **Laboratory of Applied Computational Intelligence**

Rio de Janeiro. Brazil

WEB DEVELOPER

Sep. 2013 - Aug. 2014

• Developed web application management of hydro reservoir used in energy generation with C# and .Net.

## Education

#### **University of Ottawa**

Ottawa, Canada

Sep. 2014 - Exp. Dec. 2019

PhD, ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

• Thesis Proposal: Tactile sensing and in-hand manipulation

- Technologies: ROS, C++, machine learning, data structures, tactile sensing, Inertial sensors, pressure sensors.
- · Supervisor: Emil M. Petriu, Ph.D.
- Field: Robotics, in-hand manipulation, Sensors.

## **IME - Military Institute of Engineering**

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Fev. 2011 - Jun. 2013

MSc, Systems and Computing

BSc. Computer Science

- Master thesis: Location system to support a domestic assistant robot using RSS and ZigBee.
- Technologies: Arduino, C++, ZigBee, RSS, Serial communications.
- Supervisor: Professor Paulo Fernando Ferreira Rosa, Ph.D.
- Field: Smart Environments, Wireless Sensor Networks.

#### **UFT - Federal University of Tocantins**

Palmas, Brazil

May. 2006 - Exp. Dec. 2010

• Final Project: People Recognition by the Step Sounds Using ART Type Self-Organizing Neural Networks.

- Technologies: Signal processing, Neural Networks, Python.
- Supervisor: Rafael Lima de Carvalho, D.Sc.
- Field: Artificial Intelligence, Smart Environments, Neural Networks.

# Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_

### Parallel Programming with OpenCL e OpenACC

Petrópolis, Brazil

2013

NATIONAL LABORATORY OF SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING

· Course Load: 12h

## Software and Hardware Skills

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Python, C++, C, Java, C#, UNIX shell scripting, JavaScript, SQL, Matlab, Octave, R.
- Pandas, SkLearn, Jupyter Notebooks
- ROS (Robot Operating System)
- Arduino Platform, Raspberry Pi platform.
- Git version control system.

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

• Linux, Microsoft Windows, BSD, e other Unix variants.

#### COMPUTER NETWORKING

- Wireless Networks (XBee, ZigBee radio modules).
- Networks (UDP, TCP, ARP, DNS, Dynamic routing), Linux Servers (Apache, SQL, POP, IMAP, SMTP), i2c, USB-serial.

#### CAD AND DESIGN

• Solidworks, FreeCAD, Eagle (PCB design).

## Languages\_

#### **ENGLISH**

• Understands Well, Speaks Well, Reads Well, Writes Well.

#### **PORTUGUESE**

Native.

## References\_

Petriu M. Emil - Ph.D.

Ottawa, ON, Canada

PETRIU@UOTTAWA.CA

- Professor, University of Ottawa, Electrical and Computer Engineering
- 800 King Edward Ave Ottawa, ON CANADA
- Professor Petriu is my PhD advisor.

## Thiago Eustaquio Alves de Oliveira - Ph.D.

THIAGO.OLIVEIRA@LAKEHEADU.CA

- · Assistant Professor, Lakehead University, Computer Science
- 955 Oliver Rd Thunder Bay, ON, CANADA

Thunder Bay, ON, Canada